Finding Aid for the Sterling Silliphant Papers, 1957-1985
UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections
- Motion Picture Screenplays
  - The Towering Inferno, Versions of the screenplay eventually produced as "The Towering Inferno." Screenplays and sections are arranged in chronological order of revision; each screenplay incorporates changes of the previous versions.
    - The Towering Inferno, 1973 October-1974 January; [27 folders] (Box 67, Folder 4-6, Box 68, Folder 1-5, Box 69, Folder 1-8, Box 70, Folder 1-7, Box 71, Folder 1-2)
      - Screenplay, 1973 October 26; by Stirling Silliphant; Typescript and typescript multilith. Notation "Revised Brown (1)" and "Revised 10-15-73." Several sections. (Box 68, Folder 2)
      - Screenplay, 1973 October 26; by Stirling Silliphant; Typescript. Notation "Revised Brown (2)." (Box 68, Folder 3)
      - Screenplay, 1973 October 26; by Stirling Silliphant; Typescript carbon. Pencilled notation: "Revised 10-15-73." (Box 68, Folder 4)
      - Screenplay, 1973 November 5; by Stirling Silliphant; Draft (rewrite of pink sheets of October 26, 1973). Typescript photocopy with holograph corrections. (Box 68, Folder 5)
      - Screenplay, 1973 October 1973; Revised 1973 November 16.; by Stirling Silliphant; Typescript, typescript photocopy with holograph corrections. Notation: "Yellow (3)" (Box 69, Folder 1)
      - Screenplay, Pencilled notation: 1973 November 16; by Stirling Silliphant; Typescript. Notation: "Yellow (3)." Incomplete. (Box 69, Folder 2)
      - Screenplay, 1973 November 16; by Stirling Silliphant; Typescript carbon. Notation: "Yellow (3)." Incomplete. (Box 69, Folder 3)
      - Screenplay, 1973 November 16; by Stirling Silliphant; Typescript photocopy with holograph corrections. (Box 69, Folder 4)
      - Screenplay, 1973 November 16; by Stirling Silliphant; Typescript and typescript photocopy with holograph corrections. Incomplete. (Box 69, Folder 5)
      - Screenplay, 1973 November 30; by Stirling Silliphant; Pencilled notation "Revised second draft pages. 11-30-1973." Typescript photocopy with holograph corrections. Incomplete. (Box 69, Folder 6)
      - Screenplay, 1973 November 30; by Stirling Silliphant; Pencilled notation "Revised second draft pages. 11-30-1973." Typescript carbon. Incomplete. (Box 69, Folder 7)
      - Screenplay, 1973 December 7; by Stirling Silliphant; Pencilled notation "Second draft. 12-7-1973." Typescript and typescript photocopy with holograph corrections. Incomplete. (Box 69, Folder 8)
      - Screenplay, by Stirling Silliphant; Typescript and typescript photocopy. Incomplete. (Box 70, Folder 1)
      - Screenplay, by Stirling Silliphant; Typescript. Incomplete. (Box 70, Folder 2)
      - Screenplay, by Stirling Silliphant; Typescript carbon. Incomplete. (Box 70, Folder 3)
      - Screenplay, 1973 December 12; by Stirling Silliphant; Second draft. Typescript multiluth. With blue cover. Two copies. (Box 70, Folder 4)
      - Screenplay, 1973 December 12; by Stirling Silliphant; Second draft. Typescript multiluth with holograph corrections. With blue cover. (Box 70, Folder 5)
      - Screenplay, 1974 January 11; by Stirling Silliphant; Pencilled notation: "shooting final. 1-11-74." Typescript and typescript multilith with holograph corrections. (Box 70, Folder 6)
      - Screenplay, 1974 January 11; by Stirling Silliphant; Shooting final. Typescript with holograph corrections and production notes. (Box 70, Folder 7)
      - Screenplay, 1974 January 11; by Stirling Silliphant; Shooting final. Typescript carbon. (Box 71, Folder 1)
      - Screenplay, 1974 January 11; by Stirling Silliphant; Shooting final. Typescript multilith. With beige cover. (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - The Towering Inferno, 1974 January 30; Irwin Allen's Prodcution written by Stirling Silliphant; Typescript multilith. With plastic cover. (Box 71, Folder 3)
      New opening scenes, new characterizations, new character relationships, new major incidents, complete tracking of story.
    - The Towering Inferno, 1974 February 15; [5 folders] (Box 71, Folder 4-7, Box 72, Folder 1)
      - Revised shooting final., 1974 February 15; Written by Stirling Silliphant; Typescript and typescript photocopy with holograph corrections. (Box 71, Folder 4)
      - Revised shooting final., 1974 February 15; Written by Stirling Silliphant; Typescript multilith. With green cover. Two copies. (Box 71, Folder 5-6)
      - Revised shooting final., 1974 February 15; Written by Stirling Silliphant; Typescript multilith. Pencilled notation: "not complete." With green cover. (Box 71, Folder 7)
      - Revised shooting final., 1974 February 15; Written by Stirling Silliphant; [Pencilled revision to "Seconf revised shooting final. 3-29-74."] Typescript, typescript photocopy with holograph corrections. (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - The Towering Inferno, 1974 March 29; [8 folders] (Box 72, Folder 2-9)
      - Second revised shooting final., 1974 March 29; Written by Stirling Silliphant.; Typescript with holograph corrections. Pencilled notation: "2." Incomplete. (Box 72, Folder 2)
      - Second revised shooting final., 1974 March 29; Written by Stirling Silliphant.; Typescript with holograph corrections. Incomplete. (Box 72, Folder 3)
      - Second revised shooting final., 1974 March 29; Written by Stirling Silliphant.; Typescript multilith with holograph corrections. Pencilled notation: "Original. Return to Stirling Silliphant," and "2." Incomplete. (Box 72, Folder 4)
      - Revised shooting final., 1974 February 15; Written by Stirling Silliphant.; [Pencilled revision to "Second revised shooting final. 3-29-74."] Typescript, typescript photocophy with holograph corrections. (Box 72, Folder 5)
      - Second revised shooting final., 1974 March 29; Written by Stirling Silliphant.; Typescript carbon. (Box 72, Folder 5)
      - Second revised shooting final., 1974 March 29; Written by Stirling Silliphant.; Typescript multilith with holograph corrections. With plastic cover. Incomplete. (Box 72, Folder 6)
      - Second revised shooting final., 1974 March 29; Written by Stirling Silliphant.; Typescript multilith. With beige cover. (Box 72, Folder 7)
      - Second revised shooting final., 1974 March 29; Written by Stirling Silliphant.; Typescript multilith with holograph corrections. With beige cover. (Box 72, Folder 8)
      - Second revised shooting final., 1974 March 29; Written by Stirling Silliphant.; [Pencilled revision to "Third revised shooting final. 4-18-74."] Typescript, typescript photocopy with holograph corrections. (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - The Towering Inferno, 1974 April 18; [5 folders] (Box 73, Folder 1-5)
      - Third revised shooting final., 1974 April 18; Written by Stirling Silliphant.; Typescript photocopy with holograph corrections. (Box 73, Folder 1)
      - Third revised shooting final., 1974 April 18; Written by Stirling Silliphant.; Typescript multilith. With blue cover. Three copies. (Box 73, Folder 2-4)
      - Third revised shooting final., 1974 April 18; Written by Stirling Silliphant.; [Pencilled revision to "Fourth revised shooting final. 5-16-74."] Typescript and typescript multilith with holograph corrections. (Box 73, Folder 5)
- [Newspaper and Magazine Clippings]
  - Newspaper clippings by or about Stirling Silliphant., undated.; 1 folder. (Box 27)
  - Writer's Digest. Volume 39, no. 9., 1959 September. (Box 27)
    p.18 contains article by or about Stirling Silliphant.
  - Writer's Digest. Volume 42, no. 6., 1962 June. (Box 27)
    p.19 contains article by or about Stirling Silliphant.
  - Writer's Yearbook. No. 33., 1962. (Box 27)
    p.24 contains article by or about Stirling Silliphant.
  - Magazine and newspaper clippings., 1962.; Pasted in first 5 pages of blue scrapbook. (Box 27)